CONTACT

A: 33 Oak Apple Green, Rathfarnham,

Dublin 6

P: 089 247 8762

E: paraiccooney@hotmail.com

PROFICIENT LANGUAGES

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Python

TypeScript

FRAMEWORKS & ADDITIONAL TECHNOLOGIES

Angular

Bootstrap

jQuery

API manipulation

JSON (with visualisation using DC D3,

& Crossfilter)

Jasmine (testing)

Flask

SQL

Materialize

MongoDB

Jinja

Flask,

Postgres S3 & IAM (AWS Buckets)

Diango

Stripe

SOCIAL

LinkedIn;

www.linkedin.com/in/paraic-cooney

GitHub

https://github.com/paraiccooney

PÁRAIC COONEY

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

ABOUT

A fully certified Full-Stack Developer with knowledge in a range of programming languages & frameworks. A passionate coder who is constantly exploring new technologies & possibilities.

Extensive experience compressed into a relatively short time span - a testament to an ability to comprehend & adopt complex development & evidence of a strong aptitude for coding.

Hard technical skills coupled with a soft digital marketing skill set used during the high-level planning stage. Strong communication skills & professional experience resulting in the ability to explain complex products & concepts while also maintaining & developing client relationships.

PORTFOLIO

My portfolio is comprised of my personal professional website & four websites & applications which have served as the basis for assessment for my Full-Stack Developer qualification. The below is listed in descending order with my most recent projects displayed first.

PERSONAL PROFESSIONAL ANGULAR APP https://paraiccooney.github.io/angular-portfolio-app/

Languages HTML, CSS, TypeScript

DYNAMIC NEWSPAPER WEB APPLICATION https://github.com/paraiccooney/full-stack-frameworks-project

Languages HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

INTERACTIVE RECIPE WEB APPLICATION https://github.com/paraiccooney/data-centric-project

Languages HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python

INTERACTIVE 1980S SIMON WEB GAME https://github.com/paraiccooney/simon_game

Languages HTML, CSS, JavaScript

PORTFOLIO LINKS

PORTFOLIO APPLICATION https://paraiccooney.github.io/angular -portfolio-app/

DYNAMIC NEWSPAPER WEB APP https://github.com/paraiccooney/full-stack-frameworks-project

INTERACTIVE RECIPE WEB APP https://github.com/paraiccooney/data-centric-project

INTERACTIVE 1980s SIMON WEB GAME https://github.com/paraiccooney/simo n_game

STATIC TOURISM WEBSITE https://github.com/paraiccooney/User -centric-frontend-developmentproject

PERSONAL SKILLS

Creative development
Business acumen
Digital marketing
Client management
Reliable and professional
Organised
Team player
Fast learner
Motivated

REFERENCES

Available upon request

STATIC TOURISM WEBSITE

https://github.com/paraiccooney/User-centric-frontend-development-project

Languages HTML, CSS

EDUCATION

DIPLOMA IN FULL-STACK DEVELOPMENT Code Institute | April 2019 - September 2019 Degree 1.1

DIPLOMA IN DIGITAL MARKETING
Digital Marketing Institute | October 2018 - January 2019

BACHELOR OF BUSINESS STUDIES University of Limerick | September 2010 - August 2014 Degree 2.1

LEAVING CERTIFICATE
De La Salle College Waterford | September 2004 - June 2010
420 points

WORK EXPERIENCE

For the purposes keeping this CV concise & relevant I have opted not to outline in detail each position I have held (I have been in continuous employment since graduation), however I would be happy to provide more information upon request. Please note I was working a variety of jobs in Australia from Sep '16 to Dec '17.

CLAIMS HANDLER/BROKER DWF Claims | Feb 2018 - July 2019

- My role involved customer facing after sales support for a large brokerage firm. The role revolved around managing claims on behalf of clients & involved some elements of conflict resolution.
- As part of this role I chaired periodic claims review meetings with larger clients as well as attending & facilitating liability consultations & loss adjuster meetings.
- This role is also focused on assisting the brokers/account handlers with claims queries & building claims reports in conjunction with information obtained from both the insurers & the clients.

TECHNICAL ASSISTANT/UNDERWRITING ASSISTANT Allied World Assurance Company | Nov 2014 - Aug 2016

- Part of the Operations Team which is tasked with providing support to underwriters working in the London Market. My specific line was SME which was the main focus of my role. This is a Professional Indemnity book containing Errors & Omissions & Directors & Officers cover. However part of my role has been to development my knowledge of other lines or business & systems in order to assist my teammates during their busy periods or absences.
- Tasks included logging of submissions, liaising with claims to ensure a
 sufficient claims report is on file for renewals, maintenance of policy
 folders/records, conducting outstanding information/subjectivity
 chasers (claims reports, no claims declarations, etc), double checking
 the correct details have been bound, dealing with accounts queries,
 issuing & booking endorsements, reviewing quotes & entering the
 relevant details on our systems (Dragon & Genius), issuing policy
 documentation, maintenance & contra of manual Excel logs against
 internal system run reports, preparing folders for renewal policies, fact
 checking slips, & any ad hoc tasks the underwriters required.